Guide to the Institute of Pacific Relations Records
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Oversized Materials
  - Pacific Relations Oversized Ledgers
    (The ledgers are grouped below by the AIPR division they appear to belong to, and within divisions by subject (receipts, disbursements, trial balances, other). This is not always clear: for instance, the International Publications Fund, listed here as a separate division, may be a division of the AIPR or, judging from some of the ledgers, a subdivision of the American Council. Where possible ledgers have been Boxed and listed in chronological sequence, with out-of-sequence ledgers listed afterward. There are occasional apparent overlaps between ledgers, and very frequent gaps in series.)
    - American Institute for Pacific Relations (General) Ledgers (Ledgers 1-20)
      - AIPR Accounts, 1925-1928 inclusive. (Box Flat Box 414, Volume 1)
      - AIPR Budget and condition (Statements 1925-1935) (Box Flat Box 415, Volume 2 to 3)
      - Inquiry: receipts and disbursements, 1929 July-1932 April (Box Flat Box 415, Volume 4)
      - AIPR sales receipts
        - 1941 February-1942 February (Box Flat Box 416, Volume 5)
        - 1942 February-September (Box Flat Box 416, Volume 6)
        - 1942 September-1943 July (Box Flat Box 416, Volume 7)
      - AIPR cash receipts, 1945 December-1947 June (Box Flat Box 417, Volume 8)
      - AIPR sales receipts, 1947 July-1950 February (Box Flat Box 417, Volume 9)
      - AIPR receipts
        - 1945 January-1948 December (Box Flat Box 418, Volume 10)
        - 1949 January-1957 July (Box Flat Box 418, Volume 11)
        - 1957 August-1961 August (Box Flat Box 418, Volume 12)
      - AIPR publication sales, 1942 June-1943 May (Box Flat Box 418, Volume 13)
      - AIPR disbursements
        - 1944 January-December (Box Flat Box 419, Volume 14)
        - 1945 January-1946 August (Box Flat Box 419, Volume 15)
        - 1946 September-1948 December (Box Flat Box 419, Volume 16)
        - 1949 January-1951 December (Box Flat Box 419, Volume 17)
        - 1952 January-1958 August (Box Flat Box 420, Volume 18)
        - 1958 October-1961 September (Box Flat Box 420, Volume 19)
      - AIPR trial balance (general fund, publications fund, research fund), 1947-1948 (Box Flat Box 420, Volume 20)
    - American Council (AMCO) Ledgers (Ledgers 21-27)
      - AMCO receipts and disbursements, 1929 July-1932 May (Box Flat Box 421, Volume 21)
      - AMCO receipts
        - 1932 June-1936 May (Box Flat Box 421, Volume 22)
        - 1936 June-1939 December (Box Flat Box 421, Volume 23)
        - 1940 January-1944 December (Box Flat Box 421, Volume 24)
      - AMCO disbursements
        - 1933 January-1938 February (Box Flat Box 422, Volume 25)
        - 1938 March-1943 December (Box Flat Box 422, Volume 26)
      - AMCO trial balance, 1949-1956 (Box Flat Box 422, Volume 27)
    - AIPR: International Research Fund (IRF) Ledgers (Ledgers 28-32)
      - IRF receipts and disbursements (Box Flat Box 423)
        - 1936 January-December (Box Flat Box 423, Volume 28)
        - 1951 January-1952 June (Box Flat Box 423, Volume 29)
      - IRF receipts
        - 1937 January-1942 May (Box Flat Box 423, Volume 28)
        - 1942 June-1950 December (Box Flat Box 423, Volume 29)
        - 1948 May-1949 May (Box Flat Box 423, Volume 30)
      - IRF Disbursements
        - 1937 January-1943 February (Box Flat Box 424, Volume 31)
        - 1943 March-1949 September (Box Flat Box 424, Volume 32)
    - Pacific Affairs (Ledger 33)
      - Pacific Affairs, 1951 October-1953 February (Box Flat Box 424, Volume 33)
    - AIPR: Pacific Council (PACCO) Ledgers (Ledgers 34-49)
      - PACCO meeting: Agenda: reports, draft of constitution, financial statement and budget, 1927 (Box Flat Box 425, Volume 34)
      - PACCO accounts: revenue and expenditures
        - 1929-1935 (Box Flat Box 425, Volume 35-36)
        - 1929-1935 (Box Flat Box 426, Volume 37)
      - PACCO receipts and disbursements, 1934 January-1936 December (Box Flat Box 426, Volume 38)
      - PACCO Receipts
        - 1936 December-1939 June (Box Flat Box 426, Volume 38)
        - 1939 July-1949 June (Box Flat Box 426, Volume 39)
      - PACCO publications receipts, 1956 June-1958 January (Box Flat Box 426, Volume 40)
      - PACCO disbursements
        - 1936 January-1940 September (Box Flat Box 427, Volume 41)
        - 1940 September-1944 November (Box Flat Box 427, Volume 42)
        - 1944 November-1947 November (Box Flat Box 427, Volume 43)
        - 1949 December-1951 June (Box Flat Box 427, Volume 44)
        - 1951 July-1956 November (Box Flat Box 428, Volume 45)
      - International Secretariat inquiry: disbursements
        - 1938 March-1943 May (Box Flat Box 428, Volume 46)
        - 1943 June-1947 January (Box Flat Box 428, Volume 47)
      - PACCO trial balance
        - 1949-1950 (Box Flat Box 428, Volume 48)
        - 1951 January-1954 June (Box Flat Box 428, Volume 49)
    - AIPR: International Publication Fund (IPF: sometimes AMCO Pub. Fund) (Ledgers 50-59)
      - AMCO Pub. Fund receipts and disbursements, 1935 January-1941 March (Box Flat Box 429, Volume 50)
      - IPF receipts and disbursements, 1941 April-1946 June (Box Flat Box 429, Volume 51)
      - AMCO Pub. Fund cash receipts
        - 1944 June-August (Box Flat Box 429, Volume 52)
        - 1944 September-1945 March (Box Flat Box 429, Volume 53)
        - 1945 April-December (Box Flat Box 430, Volume 54)
      - IPF receipts
        - 1949 June-1950 July (Box Flat Box 430, Volume 55)
        - 1950 July-1952 July (Box Flat Box 430, Volume 56)
        - 1952 August-1954 August (Box Flat Box 431, Volume 57)
        - 1954 August-1956 May (Box Flat Box 431, Volume 58)
      - IPF disbursements, 1942 June-1943 December (Box Flat Box 431, Volume 59)
  - Oversized Photographs and Scrapbooks
    - Photographs (2 Folders) (Box Flat Box 432)
    - Scrapbooks, 1929 October-December (3 Volumes) (Box Flat Box 432)